ILGWU. Carl Proper papers 5780/150
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Japan, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  "The Japanese Apparel Market: A Brief Industry Report"; export regulations re labeling requirements, tariffs, list of trade shows; correspondence re trade shows, incl. announcement from the U.S. Dept. of Commerce re U.S. Children's Fashion Trade Fair, 1992; lists of Japanese buying delegation and other contacts; list of Japanese organizations in the Japan Apparel Initiative (JAI); letter from the U.S. Embassy in Japan to ILG exec. asst. Parrott re possible Japanese markets for New York apparel firms, Oct. 1991; newspaper clippings
- Japan: CAF Exports Workshop, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  Letter of invitation from Fashion Exports/New York (FE/NY) to manufacturers, with description of program; list of invited firms; agenda; prepared comments to participants
- Japan: Japan Apparel Initiative (JAI) Fashion Show and Buying Mission, 1990-1992 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  A cooperative effort of the Council for American Fashion (CAF), Fashion Exports/New York, Garment Industry Development Corp. (GIDC), the Fashion Institute of Technology (FIT)'s Xport Advisory Service Extension (EASE), the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey's trading company XPORT, and the Japan External Trade Organization (JETRO). "Briefing on Japan Apparel Initiative" includes descriptive sheet with overview of each entity, description of Japanese market, agenda for August 12, 1991, briefing, preview description of October NY Women's Apparel Buying Mission (fashion show), preview description of Japan Trade Mission to Kobe Fashion Mart and Tokyo (Feb. 1992); press releases; letters of invitation to briefing; description of benefits of participating in Japan Apparel Initiative; description of fashion at Oct. 1991 show; newspaper clippings
- Japan: Japan Apparel Initiative (JAI) Fashion Show and Buying Follow-Up, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  List of Japanese participants; thank-you letter translated into Japanese; largely negative follow-up questionnaire of Japanese buyers at Oct. buying mission/fashion show; largely negative follow-up with U.S. firms participating in Oct. buying mission/fashion show; confidential memo re meeting with representative of Takishimaya department store, notes different view of Japanese demand for U.S. goods than thought by bureaucrats, poor timing of show set by Port Authority; memo from CAF director Carl Proper to ILGWU exec. asst. James Parrott re meeting with Xport/Port Authority, perception by Japanese of U.S. apparel as low quality, Dec. 5, 1990; list of jobbers/manufacturers and contractor jobs created; export surveys
- Japan: Japan Apparel Initiative (JAI) Japanese Retailers, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  Report, "Japan's Ten Leading Department Stores"; Japanese Trading Firms in the City of New York; Local Branches of Japanese Department Stores; memo re Japanese department store Isetan's request for coat manufacturers, with list; printed corporate literature of conglomerate Tomen, with cover letter from Tomen Apparel Group; correspondence with Ben, Ltd., chain store re buying trip for casual wear, men's wool sweaters
- Japan: Japan Apparel Initiative (JAI) Showroom Visits, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  Letters from Council for American Fashion to apparel design firms asking to visit showroom with representative of the Japanese External Trade Organization
- Japan: JETRO, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  Printed publications and statistical information by the Japan External Trade Organization (JETRO) re doing business in Japan; NYS Dept. of Economic Development announcement re JETRO Leisure and Recreation Import Fair 1992
- Japan: Kobe Fashion Mart, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Printed materials by the Japanese Market Center and correspondence with the Council for American Fashion (CAF), Fashion Exports/New York, and the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey re exhibiting at the Japanese trade show; lists of invited companies
- Japan: Market Studies, 1988-1992 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  "Overview of the Japanese Distribution System," by Asia Link Consulting Group; several printed editions of "Your Market in Japan" series re formal wear, sportswear, and swimwear, 1990; business facts & figures for 1992; excerpt from report, "The Apparel Market in Japan," 1988
- Mexico, 1992-1993 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  Market report prepared by Fashion Exports/New York (FE/NY); list of contacts expressing interest in NY manufacturers, 1993; fact sheets on NY firms with Spanish cover letter; brochure for export conference, "Negocios Mexico: Doing Business in Mexico," Mexico City, June 5-8, 1993; newspaper clippings
- Middle East and Motexha Trade Fair, 1987-1990 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  "The Apparel Market in Saudi Arabia," analysis for the Dept. of Commerce; memorandum from the U.S. Dept. of Commerce for prospective participants in the Motexha International Trade Show in Dubai, United Arab Emerites; announcement for 21st Motexha Childexpo International Trade Fair (Fashion 1993), 22-25 October 1992, Dubai World Trade Centre, for men's and women's wear, children's wear, fabrics, home textiles, fashion accessories, printed brochure for the U.S. Pavilion at the trade show; letter to ILGWU from president of Denmarie, Inc., of Burlington, VT, offering assistance with exports to Turkey, with enclosed information re free trade zones
- K. New York City and New York State Subseries (Box 19, Folder 10a)
- 1. New York City (Box 19, Folder 10b)
  see also "Garment Industry Development Corporation" and "Fashion Exports New York"
- Apparel Industry, 1983-1988 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  Overview of New York City garment industry, July 21, 1986; New York Garment Industry Task Force (ILGWU) memo re issues for discussion, with attached discussion papers, December 20, 1983; "Restructuring for Competitiveness within the Knitwear Production Industry in New York City," working paper by the New York Knitwear Industry Center (Queens County Overall Economic Development Corporation and Ridgewood Local Development Corporation), October 1988; census statistics
- Business Relocation Assistance Corporation (2 folders), 1984-1992 (Box 19, Folder 12-13)
  Retention and Relocation Program Rules, with cover letter to ILGWU for comment, 1992; report to the Business Assistance Relocation Assistance Corporation, "Renewing the Retention and Relocation Program," prepared by the Economic Policy and Marketing Group, Office o f the Deputy Mayor, February 1992; letters from ILG president Mazur to Mayor Dinkins and others, urging change of rules that disqualified businesses in traditional industrial neighborhoods, 1991; statements of Mazur, Manhattan borough president Ruth Messinger, and ILGWU associate director of research Walter Mankoff before the NYC Planning Commission, and press release, 1991; fact sheets re links between Manhattan and Queens in the ladies' apparel industry, consequences of displacement of garment district, 1984; list of approved manufacturers, 1986, 1988; notes of meetings and phone conversations; memos to Mazur; newspaper clippings; handwritten notes
- Business Labor Coalition, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  Known officially as the Coalition of Business, Labor and Community Organizations of New York; devoted to lobbying for national policies to benefit cities. Mission statement; draft report of task force for rebuilding the port and rail transportation for New York City; press release, "Dinkins to Present City's Agenda for Clinton Administration to New York's Congressional Delegation," November 13, 1992; remarks of chairman Maurice S. Paprin, November 17, 1992
- Economic Development Manhattan: Planning Committee Reports, 1986-1988 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  Reports of committee and correspondence between Manhattan Borough President David Dinkins and ILGWU president Mazur; Overall Economic Development Planning Committee meeting minutes, June 17, 1986; list of committee members; Progress Report, New York County Overall Economic Development Program, submitted by Manhattan Borough Development Corporation, June 1986; Draft and Draft II, New York County Overall Economic Development Program Report, June 1987; 1988 report, with comments by ILG exec. asst. James Parrott
- Economy: General, 1988-1991 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  Press release, Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, February 25, 1988; ILGWU (?) papers: "Economic Growth and Opportunities for New Yorkers," re economy under the Koch administration, "New York City's Garment Industry: Key Events, 1983-1988," "ILGWU Proposals to the City," "Garment Center Manufacturing Preservation District Zoning," March 25, 1988; newspaper clippings re abuse of funds by Harlem Commonwealth Council, job market
- Employment, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  Report, "New York City in the New Economic Environment: New Risks and a Changing Outlook," by Samuel M. Ehrenhalt, regional commissioner, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics in New York, March 1988; press release summarizing report; Women's Wear Daily newspaper clipping re report; census statistics re employment by borough, 1949-83
- Government, 1989-1993 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  City Council resolution condemning NAFTA, faxed to ILG's Carl Proper for comments, February 2, 1993; minutes of meetings between ILG officials, including president Mazur, and deputy mayor of NY, members of City Council, and other city officials; letter from Mazur to NYC mayor David Dinkins requesting meeting to plan promotion of exports to Japan, December 12, 1990; description of the New York City Alliance for International Business, Community Development Agency job readiness grant eligibility guidelines, Nov. 23, 1992; press release by NYC Ad Hoc Housing Capital Budget Coalition, "Ad Hoc Coalition Protests Elimination of Affordable Housing Production from the City's Capital Budget," April 9, 1992; newspaper clippings re job trends, misdirected public incentives, 1993 mayoral race (Giuliani); list of campaign contributions by ILGWU to all candidates for public office in NYC in 1989
- Industrial Literacy Project (ESL instruction), 1988-1992 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  A program of the New York City Industrial Technology Assistance Corporation in cooperation with ILGWU and Garment Industry Development Corporation (GIDC). Grant proposal and correspondence with ILGWU president Mazur, 1991; grant proposal for New Jersey project and correspondence with K-Mart re on-site English as a Second Language (ESL) training, 1992; Federal Register notice/request for proposals re Department of Education National Workplace Literacy Program, 1992; draft of study by St. John's School of Law professor David Gregory re workplace literacy, cover letter to Mazur, September 27, 1988. see also GIDC Advisory Committee on Training
- New York Urban Coalition, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  Critical analysis of Urban Coalition draft, "A Vision of a Just New York: The Decade Ahead," March 18, 1988; analysis by exec. asst. James Parrott, June 14, 1998; Mazur's comments to Urban Coalition on draft report, August 5, 1988; agenda and minutes of the Board of Directors, March 16, 1988; fund development statement and cover letter to Mazur, noting expectation that board members make a personal financial gift to the coalition, September 6, 1988; correspondence re luncheon honoring U.S. Senator Daniel Patrick Moynihan and Rep. Charles Rangel
- Real Estate: Reports and Articles, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  Drafts of "Real Estate Pressures and the New York City Garment Industry: The Pressing Need for a Public Policy Response," with handwritten comments (by ILGWU vice president Susan Cowell?); April 4, 1986; "The Outlook for New York City in Real Estate and Construction," by Seymour B. Durst; "New York City Garment Center Study: Program and Zoning Recommendations," and "New York City Economic Development Programs and Strategies: Manufacturing, Office, and Small Business Sectors," June 1986, Policy Analysis Division, NYC Office for Economic Development; Dept. of City Planning; newspaper clippings, including special issue of Crain's New York Business
- Real Estate: Reports Garment Center Study, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  "NYC Garment Center Study: Program and Recommendations," NYC Office for Economic Development, Department of City Planning, Public Development Corporation October 1986
- Real Estate: Reports Garment Center Enforcement Project, 1990-1992 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  A project of the Office of Midtown Enforcement, a department of the mayor's office. Final report, October 1991; use & occupancy survey, August 1, 1991; quarterly reports, 1990, 1992; newspaper clipping reporting drop in crime with increased police presence
- Real Estate: Commercial Rent, 1985-1989 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  Memos of conversations with City Councilmen re pending legislation; testimony by ILGWU president Mazur in favor of Commercial Rent Binding Arbitration legislation (Intro. 1237), November 15, 1988; against substitute bill (Intro. 1245), June 14, 1989; testimony by Dennis Keating, assoc. prof. of law, Cleveland State Univ., in favor of Intro. 1237, June 9, 1989; letters from labor unions lobbying for passage of Intro. 914A; ILGWU press release re Intro. 1237, June 9, 1989; Fact Sheet, Commercial Rent Binding Arbitration New York City Council Intro. 914A, prepared by ILGWU; list, Firms Forced to Move as a Result of Rent Increase; memo summarizing survey of firms displaced due to rent pressures, July 9, 1985; memo re displaced firms and garment center zoning, January 7, 1987; Housing and Vacancy Report, prepared for the NYC Department of Housing Preservation and Development, April 1988; background points for Manhattan Borough President Dinkins cable show, "Should Manufacturing Be Retained in Manhattan?", related correspondence; statement by Dinkins on inclusionary zoning, May 21, 1987; statement by Dinkins in favor of vacant building program, March 10, 1988; newspaper clippings re structure of New York City Council, negative impacts of rent control; handwritten notes
- Real Estate: Industrial Loft Advisory Council, 1984-1989 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  Meeting minutes; letter/report to NYC mayor Ed Koch re preserving industrial space; newspaper clippings; testimony by ILGWU president Mazur before the NY City Council on Intro 914A, Commercial Rent Binding Arbitration, Nov. 15, 1988; testimony by Thomas Van Arsdale, president, New York City Central Labor Council; testimony by head of NY Chamber of Commerce against commercial rent control; testimony by NYC Corporation Counsel; testimony by the NY regional vice president of the American Arbitration Association; notes re telephone conversation; newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Real Estate: SoHo Alliance, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  Report, "The Prospect of Hotels in Soho," prepared for the SoHo Alliance by planning consultants Abeles Phillips Preiss & Shapiro; letter from Friends of SoHo to NY City Planning Commission "vehemently" opposing hotel development; letter to Mayor Dinkins; newspaper clippings
- Real Estate: Times Square Redevelopment Project, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  Testimony on the Draft Environmental Impact Statement for the 42nd Street Development Project, by Jay Mazur, general secretary-treasurer, ILGWU, expressing concern with impact of Times Square redevelopment on adjacent garment district, leading to commercial conversions of production facilities and higher rents, March 26, 1984; testimony by Mazur at UDC hearing on redevelopment project, asking for balanced economic planning, mitigation measures, September 6, 1984; comments of the ILGWU to the UDC, May 1984; press release, "Union Calls for Measures to Counteract Effect of 42nd Street Redevelopment on Garment Center," Sept. 6, 1984; Statement by Mayor Edward I. Koch, Comptroller Harrison J. Golden, and City Council President Carol Bellamy, pledging to work with ILGWU to preserve and create apparel jobs in the garment district and elsewhere in the city, Nov. 8, 1984; statement by Dr. Roger Waldinger, City College of New York, "The Impact of the 42nd Street Redevelopment Plan on the Garment Industry," presented to the Board of Estimate hearings, October 25, 1984, arguing that merchandise mart plans for apparel should be abandoned; draft of report by Tom Davidoff (?) with cover note asking for comment by ILG staff; newspaper clippings; oversized poster
- Real Estate: Trends, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  Newspaper clippings re real estate changes and events; Crain's New York Business paper, "Changing face of New York"
- Sweatshops, 1991-1992 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  Letter from Chinese Staff & Workers' Association asking for support in campaign against sweatshops in NYC, March 31, 1991, with attached fact sheet re Wai Chang Fashions, "Brooklyn garment shop owes workers over $100,000 in unpaid wages" and sample letter to NYS Dept. of Labor; correspondence between Assemblyman Frank Barbaro, chairman of the Labor Committee, and ILG president Mazur; transcript of testimony by Mazur before the committee re effectiveness of Apparel Industry Task Force, created by Barbaro, March 20, 1992; testimony by NYS Labor Commissioner John Hudacs; transcript of interview with Chinese worker; copies of four bills in Senate and Assembly to increase civil and criminal penalties for violating labor laws and holding manufacturers equally liable for violations by their contractors; certified letter from U.S. Dept. of Labor's Wage and Hour Division re enforcement of Fair Labor Standards Act, and attached letter sent to every manufacturer, contractor, and subcontractor in the U.S., citing high levels of noncompliance, stressing prohibition against homework in apparel industry, March 6, 1992; press release from U.S. Dept. of Labor re temporary restraining order against NYC garment manufacturer, April 30, 1992; newspaper clippings. see also "Sweatshops" (general subject files)
- Workforce Development Commission, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  Letter from NYC mayor Dinkins to ILG president Mazur inviting him to become a member of the Workforce Development Commission, with attached concept paper, June 28, 1993; text of address to commission (by Mazur?), "ILGWU Experience with Education, Training, Job Creation, Job Retention, Job Enhancement"; report by the commission, "New York City Labor Force Demand and Supply," heavily hand- annotated with critical comments (by Mazur?); draft recommendations ("confidential"), December 21; drafts of Research Project Approach, Discussion with Commissioners, hand annotated, September 14 ("confidential"); committee minutes, agendas, remarks by Mazur, notes
- Workforce Development Commission: Task Forces, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  Committee minutes of education task force and demand and supply task force; issues papers
- Workforce Development Commission: Task Forces on Training, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  Training committee minutes; preliminary findings, training, placement, and support services, Oct. 13; issues papers
- Workforce Development Commission: Worker Focus Groups, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  Transcripts of worker focus groups re workplace training programs, November; confidential summary and discussion by consultant McKinsey, November 16
- Workforce Development Commission: ILGWU Internal Discussion, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  Draft of letter to deputy mayor to be sent over Mazur's signature, with memo to several advisors seeking input, August 18; notes re recommendations for ILG participation in commission, internal ILG and Council for American Fashion (CAF) memos re issues
- 2. New York State, 1984-1988 (Box 20, Folder 14a)
- Apparel Industry: New York State, 1984-1988 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  Narrative, "The Apparel Industry in New York State: A Statistical Profile," prepared by the NYS Dept. of Commerce, Bureau of Business Research, March 1986; NYS Department of Labor report, "Occupational Needs in the 1980s: New York State 1987-1989" (projections); U.S. Dept. of Labor employment, hours, and earnings survey data, 1939-82 and supplement for 1980-84; overview of apparel industry, New York State, 1985; NYS apparel and knitting mill statistics by county, prepared by ILGWU Research Dept., based on data from U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1973-86; U.S. Dept. of Commerce/Bureau of the Census "County Business Patterns: New York" by industry, 1981-84; newspaper clipping
- Economic Development/Enterprise Zones, 1985-1992 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  Department of Economic Development program. Program description; "Rebuilding Our Cities: The Case for Enterprise Zones," report by the Legislative Commission on Public-Private Cooperation, Senator Roy M. Goodman, Chairman, September 18, 1985; statements on enterprise zones, submitted by ILGWU president Jay Mazur before the Senate Finance Committee, June 17, 1992; before the House Ways and Means Committee, July 18, 1991; by ILG president Sol Chaikin before the Senate Finance Committee, April 21, 1992 and May 3, 1983; talking points for meeting with Housing Secretary Henry Cisneros, August 6, 1993; memos to Cisneros, April 1 and 6, 1993
- Economic Development/Enterprise Zones, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  Letter from ILGWU president Mazur to NYS AFL-CIO president Edward J. Cleary re concerns expressed to Economic Development Zone Review Commission; draft of legislation; transcript of testimony before hearing by local EDZ officials from Elmira, Oswego, Plattsburgh, Auburn, Ogdensburg, and Essex County, March 6; state-by-state list of enterprise zone incentives; meeting agendas; handwritten notes
- Economic Development/Enterprise Zones: Comptrollers Audits, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  Office of State Comptroller Report of Examination: Economic Development Zone Program, September 1, 1990; report by Office of the State Deputy Comptroller for the City of New York, October 23, 1990
- Economic Development/Enterprise Zones: Review Commission Hearing, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  Transcript of hearing re Progress and Effectiveness of the NYS Economic Development Zones Program, held by Special Economic Development Zone Review Commission, April 3
- Economic Development/Enterprise Zones: Review Commission Reports, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  Updated proposed findings and recommendations, sent to commission members for comment, May 7, 1991; comments by ILGWU president Mazur, May 30, 1991; interim report, "Summary Findings and Recommendations of the Economic Development Zones Review Commission," June 19, 1991; final draft, for commission review, October 4, 1991; memo re future of EDDZ program; Mazur's recommendation, April 23, 1991; New York State Economic Development Zones Program Review Commission Final Report, November 1991
- Economic Development/Enterprise Zones: Articles, 1978-1994 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  Scholarly and newspaper articles on enterprise zones, most of it negative; AFL-CIO Reviews the Issues: Empowerment Zones and Enterprise Communities: Promise and Pitfalls, June 1994; "Enterprise Zones: New Directions in Economic Development," Roy E. Green, editor (Sage Publications); "The Political Economy of States' Job-Creation Business Incentives," Bennett Harrison and Sandra Kanter, AIP Journal, October 1987
- Excelsior Fund, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  A program of the Governor's office. Description of program, list of Board of Directors and advisory committees; press releases announcing creation of award recognizing quality performance and cooperative labor-management relations in public, private, and educational sectors; noting first recipients; printed booklet describing criteria; newspaper clipping from Crain's NY Business, noting loan pool for midsized companies; memo to ILGWU president Mazur
- Garment Industry Advisory Committee, 1989-1992 (Box 21, Folder 5)